### Contact

keshtelmek@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/sergey-rozum (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

Research
Data Analysis
Report Writing

# Sergey Rozum

Head of UX Research at Sberbank

Moscow

# Summary

A researcher with wide experience in different types of research. I have worked on marketing, political and user experience studies. Also worked in different types of companies - from startup agency to the largest bank in the country.

Can conduct a study using only napkin and pencil. But also can use R and Python or SPSS, if needed.

Know how to use both quantitative and qualitative modes of research design. And yeah, I know something about mixed-mode methods and grounded studies.

SNA, SEM, QCA, CQC - can say which one of these abbreviations isn't a sociological method.

Have experience with sample sizes from 5 to 30 000 respondents. I love coming up with new methodological cadavers for more efficient research. Also, I'm obsessed with data visualization and know what data/ink ratio is.

# Experience

Sberbank

Head of UX-Reseasch

September 2019 - Present (1 year 6 months)

As a Head of UX-Research at Sberbank's "Business Products" cluster, I am doing the

research of b2b products (mostly Cust Dev, Design Thinking, in-person & remote UX Testing, sometimes ethnography or diary studies)

Part of my responsibilities is coordination of research process (speaking with internal customers, consulting and couching other researchers and product owners, organization of knowledge base).

Came up with "Methodology as a Service" thing - if product owners or designers want to do research by themselves, I help them to find a suitable methodology, and support them in every phase of the study.

Made methodology for expert evaluation of Voice User Interfaces.

### MTS Group

Lead UX-Researcher

December 2018 - September 2019 (10 months)

My responsibilities as a lead UX-Researcher:

- Conducting UX-studies, cust dev sessions, in-depth interviews
- Establishing a lean research process
- Instructing researchers, product owners, and designers
- · Development of research templates, regulations, methodology
- Testing and putting into operation of new methodologies
- Lecturing in the corporate university

#### Fabuza

**Usability Analyst** 

December 2016 - December 2018 (2 years 1 month)

Usability Factory is a software company that makes remote UX-test software and works as an agency (doing research on their own platform).

### Mostly I have been:

- · Conducting remote usability-studies
- · Hypothesis formulation
- Writing scenarios for UX-test sessions
- Cleaning and analyzing data from tests
- · Writing study reports
- Reporting study results to clients

And sometimes I trained clients to make their own studies using our platform.

#### **VCIOM**

Assistant in Department of Monitoring and Electoral Research April 2016 - October 2016 (7 months)

- monitoring studies
- social and electoral analytics
- questionnaire design
- · analytical report writing
- a methodological study of social research

Tns Global Market Research Interviewer March 2015 - July 2015 (5 months) Moscow, Moscow City, Russia

### **VCIOM**

Research Assistant Intern
July 2014 - September 2014 (3 months)

Moscow, Moscow City, Russia

# Education

Higher School of Economics

Master's degree, Sociology · (2016 - 2018)

Moscow State University of Transport (MIIT) Bachelor's degree, Sociology · (2011 - 2016)

Russian University of Humanities
High School Diploma, Government Management · (2009 - 2011)